We're not even going to talk about all
these gurus online who are like, "Oh, your
first $10,000 a month." Something I want
us to think about instead is your
first $10,000 email. Now,
for some of you in the position you're in,
it could sound wild,
it could sound unimaginable.
But if you stick with the process
that we're going to go through in this
video, you
can really honestly one day do a $10,000
email
from one single email.
It could be for a fitness challenge,
could be for a product launch,
could be for a
book sale.
So the way I want us to think of email
marketing to begin with is
imagine email marketing
is like chatting someone up on a night
out.
Social media is where you see the hot
person from across the bar, but
rather than going up
and chatting to them
and chewing their ear off where they're
like, "Piss off," you walk up politely,
and you get their number.
And then you go out
and you have a good night.
They have a good night.
Then you organize a date the following
week. That is what email marketing is.
Trying to sell on social media
is like trying to go up to people on a
night out and
asking them for a shag.
Using email marketing
is like leaving the club with
20 numbers.
So throughout this video,
there's probably four
or five main key things
that we're going to cover off,
and those things are,
one,
kind of how I grew my email list to be
over 500,000.
But that's more so you can understand how
you can grow a massive contact
list.
How the world of email marketing has
changed in 2024,
because the last 12 months,
so much is different.
If I did this webinar a year ago,
it would've been so
different. How to plan
and script emails yourself and not relying
on having to hire people to do it for you.
And probably finally,
why many of you watching this don't
actually need a marketing
department to do this for you.
And better yet, those of you that are
here watching this,
you're going to have the opportunity to
ask questions as we go
along. So you get to,
as we go through this,
think up ideas and questions,
put them in the comments,
and we're going to stop and
go through questions and answers.
But before I tell you about how I grew my
own list to 500,000
subscribers,
let's first look into how the landscape of
email marketing has changed
in 2024. Now,
a quick recap for any of you that
don't use email marketing yet. We
are not sending emails from a Yahoo
or a Gmail
account. We are using a software
that collates, sends,
and organizes contact
information on our behalf.
I will share some of my favorite platforms
a little bit later.
But first of all,
let's just appreciate how great it is
that we can grow a database
over time,
and then whenever we need to poke them
or remind them about
whatever it is, we can.
The best way I can show you the power of
email marketing is
this. Right now we have
178 people watching live,
and how did most of you get this reminder?
Through emails.
You would've got an email 24 hours before,
one hour before,
15 minutes before I even broadcasted this,
and all of those emails were
pre-written and organized
and actually put through an email provider
called
Klaviyo. Now,
the email list created for this
event was unique, and it
was grown using paid adverts
and organic posts.
So there were organic posts
that went on my socials, and there
were paid ads that
we could target people
that we thought would be right for this.
And then I've just posted on LinkedIn,
Threads, Facebook, et cetera.
Now, a quick side note.
While I think about it,
one of the main things that's
changed in the past 18 months
is the fact there's never been more places
you can
put sign-up links.
So trying to get people on your email list
has actually never
been easier. For instance, on YouTube,
there's now something called a community
wall where you can post pictures,
and you can embed a URL.
So we're starting to see a for you style
page even coming on
LinkedIn and even Instagram Threads,
although it's a bit shit,
it's still a place
to easily post written content,
and then we have Twitter as well.
So we have all of these places
that we can now embed and put links
that people can
click to go to a place.
And talking of written content,
I actually have an offer
for you guys watching this video,
and there will be a link in the
description the
whole time,
and it's basically a discount to my
mentorship where you get not only
my email marketing course,
but you get a course on short-form content
creation,
the Email Advantage, which
is my email marketing course.
And I'm releasing a YouTube course called
The Silver Play Button, and it's all
bundled into one big course with one off
fee.
But anyway, we'll get into
that a little bit later.
But if at any point you're like,
"Oh my God, this guy
knows how to help my business," there's
going to be a link in the description.
We're going to keep it there.
But back to what I was saying.
Written content is coming back.
So you can use that written content to
send
people to your email list where they can
get more written content.
So think of it this way.
What is more likely to get people to want
to read your stuff than reading your
stuff in the first place?
Unargy. So you think about even carousels,
people swiping it, they
will screenshot their tweets
and swipe across seven times or whatever.
So
not only have you got thousands of emails
for this event to nudge people about this
video,
those who don't show up to this today
because maybe they're asleep or
whatever,
I still get to email them about it.
So if you think about the power of email
marketing,
even the people that don't show up, bam,
here's the video that you missed.
Even if they don't watch the video, bam,
I can reengage them and send them an offer
to what I was just saying before.
So we'll get into these kind of strategies
a
little bit later in the video.
But another thing to think about is,
even though it
can seem insignificant
that there's 200 people watching this,
when I've got a
following of much, much larger,
being able to use email
marketing to send the right amount of
people to this.
The reason I'm not blasting this all over
my Instagram is everyone here has a
business,
and if you can use email marketing to not
grow a huge list of
hundreds of thousands of people,
but the right amount of people that
are good for
your business,
you can communicate with them.
And this is the power of email marketing.
It's the power of getting email addresses,
and it's the power of not just getting
people that are right for your business,
they're perfect for your business.
So before I get into the next bit,
I know that sometimes I do tend to waffle
about
email marketing. But
if you have some very basic questions on
email
marketing,
fire them below in the comments,
and we'll look into it in about three
or four minutes.
And I'm not going to be like, "Oh,
you're so stupid.
You should know this,"
or anything like that. This
is a safe space.
You can ask what you like.
So one of the newest big things in 2024
is something that I was actually quite
against for a long time.
I used to think they
looked a little bit desperate.
I thought they looked a little bit shit,
but
I didn't really think they could benefit a
business.
But this one thing that's actually been
something I use a lot now is
chatbots. So when some people say, "Oh,
DM me"
or comment the word whatever,
some people have had staff
that they're kind of
closing in the DMs,
but you can actually get chatbots to do it
for you.
And the one that I use is called ManyChat.
Now,
ManyChat has an automation feature that's
been around since about 2015,
but recently it became acquired as a
partner to Meta, who own Facebook and
Instagram. And the integrations that
are possible using ManyChat to scoop
up email addresses have become phenomenal.
They have leveled up in a way
that over the last three, six,
nine months,
getting email addresses, again,
like I said before, has never been easier.
So long story short,
you can head into ManyChat,
and you can create it to your
Instagram and your Facebook,
and you can create prompts so that people,
if they
send you a word, they get a link.
So for any of you that
are watching this right
now, just to prove it,
if you're watching this on your laptop,
feel free to DM me
on Instagram,
and if you send me the word "email one,"
so email
followed by the number one,
you will get a response from me.
And I'm not even touching my phone.
So I'm just sat here doing a webinar,
and this is to prove to the point that you
can send people through,
whether it's your sales funnel
or process or whatever,
through automation. Now, again,
if you send that to me, boom, what do you
get?
You get an offer for the mentorship link
in the description. Same thing.
It's not a sign-up page,
but the power of this
is what I'm saying is you can give
people verbal cues or written cues,
and then they can perform an
action,
and that action can send them closer to
going towards your email list.
So
these automations at the moment,
I have them set up everywhere.
If anyone comments
or uses the word "calorie calculator"
or even "calculator," they
get it. Free email sequences,
which I'm going to explain a little bit
more in some
detail, but they, in essence,
do the work for me so
that anyone watches the reel,
Facebook posts, or anything,
actually feels compelled for more
information, can
type or DM me if they want to keep it
private.
Because some people might actually not
want people to know that they're
considering buying a program or whatever.
So if you get this right,
the more comments on the
post that you get as well,
it's only going to feed into the
algorithm.
So let's say you do say on something, "Oh,
DM..." I think you should use funny
words as well.
My first ever time using the chatbot,
I said, "DM the word daddy."
And people were just commenting "daddy"
because they didn't know what was going to
come. But I actually think this
is kind of the death of the click the link
in bio,
because for years we used to sit here
and go, "Oh, click the link in bio."
But I do feel that that
is probably the position we're in at the
moment.
I feel like some people are, "Oh,
I don't want to click on your Linktree,"
and then
there's all these offers,
and it's just a bit shit.
So,
I do feel like this
was a bit too long-winded.
Never felt personal.
And it was something I didn't think I'd
loathe it as much as I do.
The only thing I hate more than that
is when people go, "Hey," and drop me a
follow.
Don't do that. Don't do that.
You're better than that.
Click the link in bio
is one cringey thing,
but asking people to follow you
is more cringe-worthy.
But do you know what
is better than getting
a follow?
Infinitely times better than a follow
is getting an email address.
So those of you in content,
instead of trying to say to people, "Oh,
drop me a
follow," wouldn't it be better to use the
oxygen that's coming out of your mouth to
say to people, "Hey, do this.
I will give you something in return for
your email."
Because you can't
fly first class with the amount of
followers you got.
Emirates aren't like, "Oh,
you got a million followers.
Jump on the plane." You need emails
because you need sales. Okay.
We're about to get into what most people
call lead magnets, but I like to call them
squeezes because you're squeezing people
for their data.
And just before we go into that,
let me check if there
are any questions that may
be worth answering before we depart onto
the next chapter of email
domination. Hope you guys
are all enjoying it so far.
Okay,
we're going to get into the Q&A number
one.
All right, I've got some questions here,
and they've been cleverly sent to my
phone,
which is just organization. Okay,
Marco Mac:
"As a startup,
when would you recommend starting an email
list?" So
if you're going to be doing any kind of
marketing efforts anywhere online,
it makes sense that you
are scooping data of people,
whether they're
trialing, even if someone
was to go into your gym, for
instance, to do like a day pass,
if someone was to do anything,
why wouldn't you want to collect data of
people?
So I think it's something you do straight
away because it's going to be part of
your sales funnel.
So any business you're in,
you're going to have
brand awareness, engagement,
then you're going to have prospects,
leads,
current clients, retention,
and through that funnel,
you're going to want people's
information.
So start a list as soon as you can
straight away.
Even if you're like, "Oh,
I've just qualified as PT,"
or you're just starting to
business, get that as quick as you can.
Satish Mistry says,
"Do people even read their emails?" So
you're showing your age
a bit here, mate.
I can tell you're probably a generation
below me, probably Gen Z,
think, "Oh, emails are old school."
But imagine this, right?
Your clients are going to be people
that earn good money. They are.
They're going to be your best clients.
You don't really want to train poor
people.
Now, when you deal with wealthy people,
they often have time they put
aside to pay off their Amex,
to book their flights
if they do it themselves.
Even from an administrative point of view.
Online banking,
all of these important things that
are crucial to us.
When you buy a plane ticket flying
somewhere, you
have it in your inbox.
People still read emails,
especially professionals.
And when we look at the majority of people
that earn six or seven figures, they
work within corporate organizations where
the majority of communications happen via
email. So just because you
and your friends may not talk to each
other via email,
it doesn't discredit the form of
communication.
And here's another thing.
This has actually been done.
Tim Ferriss put this in his book,
"The 4-Hour Workweek."
Tim Ferriss asked students to reach out to
famous people, and the way you
get through to a famous person
is to email them.
So I'm not going to pretend I'm grandiose
or super famous or whatever, but
my inbox has no gatekeepers.
You go to my Instagram, you'll get lost in
a sea of thousands of random DMs. You try
texting me, I'll block you or whatever.
But if you email me
and my email address
is everywhere on the internet, I reply to
everyone. If it's spam,
obviously I don't do it, whatever.
But- I even emailed Joe Wicks when I
was ripping into him, and I got a
response in about seven minutes. So
if you want to get through to people,
trust me,
email's the way to do it. Again,
if you were going to try and sue someone,
you'd
email them. If you wanted to get legal,
you'd email.
You think about when you do the deeds on
buying a property, you negotiate
with lawyers over email.
All the important things happen over
email.
And people don't just blase read their
emails.
You don't read your emails on a Tinder
date, right?
You're like, "Nah." When it's emails,
I'm sitting down,
I'm putting my headphones
on, I'm giving it my current attention.
Imagine this, even
if you get halfway through an email
and you haven't finished
reading it, you mark it as unread.
No one does that with WhatsApps.
No one does that with texts. Jamie Young,
"Is there a sweet spot when it
comes to cadence? This
is for consumer physical product." We'll
get into this.
Jason the fitness coach, "What
are we meant to email about?" We're going
to get
into this. Jamie,
"I have a LinkedIn email newsletter with
5,000
subs. Not coaching related,
but Google Ads. I currently have no offer.
How would you start to monetize either
LinkedIn newsletter or email list?" Well,
you need an offer. Otherwise,
you're going to be like a priest with a
fucking
14-inch cock.
Finding out a dude's got a 14-inch cock,
you're like, "Fucking hell, this is the
best thing in the world." You could do
whatever you want with it.
You could just get it out at dinner
parties and impress people.
But then the second you find out they're a
priest, you're like, "Oh, what the fuck
are you going to do with that?" So
you have to have an offer,
and without that, it's just a blog.
Email marketing without an offer
is just a blog.
Okay,
so we're going to move into the next bit
because as we go along...
All right, actually, Shane Carberry,
quickly,
"Any tips on how to keep your list
engaged before you have anything to sell?
I'm not in the fitness industry." I'm so
glad you guys are not in the fitness
industry. "But I am in coaching
and don't want to sell shit just to keep
them
engaged." We're going to move on to this
as well.
I've actually got something we're going to
cover off in a second, but these are
good questions, and hopefully,
as we stop for these different Q&A
segments,
you can get to understand a little bit
more.
So
yeah,
I've kind of planned these bits ahead.
But as we go through the modules,
hopefully, the questions will keep coming.
So
again,
don't forget to check out
that link in the description at some point
in this video.
So we
celebrated the death of the link in bio.
It died a death.
Another thing that died this year
was the PDF, right?
I've seen so many crappy PDFs be used as
part of a squeeze page, and I think
they've personally been done to death.
If you want to get someone's email,
do not make a PDF.
That's like the bread and butter go-to is,
"Oh, if I want your email address, I've
made a PDF with a workout on it," or,
"I've made a PDF with ways
to lose fat," or,
"I made a PDF with recipe..." They're done
to death.
I'll explain why, right? So for instance,
I work with a lot of personal trainers,
and they seem to think a protein guide
or a fat loss guide will do, but they just
won't. People have seen so many of them,
and too many of you are kind of
graduates from the school of Canva,
and not the good kind.
Even if you do get a designer to make it,
the functionality of it is
gone because it's been made to look nice
and not actually be good.
And if you end up getting bum-railed by
the number one biggest mistake in email
marketing in many departments,
it would be this.
You make it too long. The thing is,
firstly, you make this nice PDF, and
the ordeal of scrolling a PDF
is a pain in the arse,
not to mention people finding
where you left off.
If you read half a PDF,
you can't come back to where you were.
You've got to scroll down
and find out where it was.
And when people ask me to do blurbs on
their books, right, where you've got to
write something nice on the back of it,
they'll send me a PDF version of their
book, and I look at it from WhatsApp,
and I'm like, "Nah, this is too long."
And I
never come back to it.
I make up a blurb on books.
If you see my name on the back of a book,
I didn't read it.
And that's more damaging than anything in
this scenario.
If you send someone an asset for their
email address and that asset is shit, you
are fucked from the off.
If your PDF is too short, it's shit.
Now, if your PDF is too long,
it's equally shit because they can't be
arsed to
finish it. And even if your PDF
is the right length, well, if the design
is cheap and it's not right
and it doesn't serve a functionality,
it's also
shite. A PDF is just so hard to nail.
But the real bummer is this.
No one really wants another flipping PDF.
No one wants, "Oh, I really wish there
was a well-curated PDF." When I look
at trends right now that are killing it,
and the only thing that I could call this
for your business is Trendbalone for
Sales, and that thing is known as an email
autoresponder. Now, I know
that sounds about as appealing as having a
fucking wine
bottle shoved up your arse,
but let me explain. Okay?
So my first email responder came, brr,
10 years
ago. Probably 10 years ago. There
was a marketing guy, and apologies
if any of you
heard this before. There
was a guy in Ireland,
called Evil Bull Genius, and
basically, he ran a paid ad.
It came up on my Facebook, and
when I saw it, it said,
"52 ways in 52 days to improve your
business." And I signed up.
Just signed up to be cool. And every day,
he was emailing me with something
I haven't really thought about in
business.
I was like, "Oh, this is pretty clever,
this." And some days, I'd be like, "Oh,
where's Evil Bull Genius?" The next day,
boom, he's in there.
I was, "Oh, sweet,
cool." Then after 52 days,
he then plugged his book,
and I was like, "You clever bastard,
right?" Then I realized he wasn't emailing
me every day.
He'd just pre-written 52 emails.
And I was like,
"That's great," because I already now know
his business.
He's got paid ads. He's then going to pay,
let's say he pays 50
cents per email address because he's going
to have a certain amount of impressions.
They're going to get a certain amount of
clicks, and a certain amount of clicks can
get a certain amount of emails.
Then even if it costs him 50 cents
per email address,
if he has one in 10 people buy his
book where he has a $5 markup,
he now has a machine where he puts money
into paid ads,
and money comes out the end in book sales.
And I was like, "This is great."
And people are spending weeks of their
life in
front of him. Now, it was only when I
was making my business mentorship course
that
I was telling this story where I was like,
"I should probably set up an email
responder." So I'm going to explain to you
very briefly my email
autoresponders,
and just to make it very clear,
send email one, wait 24 hours,
send email two, wait 24 hours.
So I've one for my coaching app,
and it's four and a half months of
emails every day. I got my three books.
I sat here, and I turned page to page,
going through the chapters in the book,
and
I turned them into emails. Now,
you probably think what kind of psychopath
would
sit there and write four
and a half months of emails?
But the thing is,
I actually just stayed ahead of the
automation as I was adding to
it. Now, another main one that I use
is a 30-day sequence of business
revolution that I use for this course.
But this video is just about emails.
So if you do want those 30 days of
nuggets, then
We'll deal with that another time.
But
there are 30 days,
I actually just copied them.
I just copied them.
It worked for me.
I'm not afraid to say it.
Evil Genius, if you're watching this,
I copied you. Right?
They're my emails, but it was your idea.
So, and that's what you should do.
That's probably for the YouTube course,
if you see something working, replicate it
anyway.
So even if you don't think you'll do
business with me, you should probably
consider signing up to some of my email
autoresponders the next time you see them
on social media,
and you can then see the success leaves
clues, and then
you'll be like, "Okay, cool.
I got emails from James,
and I felt more compelled.
I feel like I trust him better," whatever
it is.
My publishers are going to be fucking
fuming.
They're going to be, "Hold on,
we paid you hundreds of thousands of
pounds in
advances for you to put it all into a free
email sequence." I'm sorry, Harper
Collins.
What does this mean for you? Well,
you need to reverse engineer the needs of
your
demographic. So I think rather than a PDF,
that your best bet is to create a
solution that you can deliver via email.
Okay? Not a PDF, via email. So let's look
at some examples off the top of my head.
Let's say you're a Brazilian jujitsu
instructor, let's say,
because I want to use examples
that aren't related to the fitness
industry because
I hate
the fitness industry.
I'm sick to death of it.
I'm held captive in here.
Whatever industry you're in,
we need to think of a pain point.
So for the you guys out there that
are doing coaching for whatever, what
is the
pain point of a jujitsu instructor?
That your jujitsu sucks.
Okay, that could be a bit harsh.
So instead, let's try
and be more constructive
with that pain point at the same time.
So let's think of a pain point.
Let's delve in deep.
What does the instructor want to do for
that person?
Let's think. For the past six months,
although you've attended class, your
performance has stagnated,
and everyone around you seems to get
better faster than
you, and you have your bread
and butter submissions and moves,
but the idea of
jumping into a six-hour tutorial never
seems to work. Cool.
Now you will think that I,
as the instructor, understand your
pain points.
So I've kind of stabbed you with the
knife. I've twisted it a bit.
Now what we need to do
is bring a solution,
a solution compelling enough that that
person will think, "Oh, man,
maybe I should give this person my email
address." So
you would need to then create a content
strategy that entails maybe BJJ moves,
positions, and problem-solving.
And if your social media channel
is about flipping secondhand motorcycle
parts,
it's not going to make sense to do a
squeeze page about Brazilian jujitsu.
Right?
So it has to have something to do with
your business.
So let's formulate a solution off the top
of my head.
"Hey, guys,
I created a 12-week free program where
each day you get sent a
submission, a pass, or a clever trick
that you can use to improve your jujitsu.
It's not in a PDF.
It's actually sent daily,
and they take no longer than two
minutes to watch or read. And
if you want these for free,
then you can DM the word
jits,
and I will send you the link to sign up."
Amazing. Cool. So now you can go away
and create this.
You don't have to have a PDF,
and you don't even need to do 90 days of
emails. You can just write an email
and be ahead of that person.
So you write one clever email a day for 90
days, just be a few days ahead of the
sequence. You could use pictures, videos.
Either way,
you're going to accrue a shitload of what
we would call in the industry
goodwill, which is the currency
that we're really after.
Even this video, right?
I'm a mad bastard that's going to give you
so much value
from a webinar that at the end of it,
you're going to feel like you're in so
much
debt to me, which you will.
By the end of this video,
you're going to be like, "I
might as well just give him some money
because this guy's revolutionized my life
for free." And this
is what we should be doing as part of a
good email marketing
strategy.
We should be making people think
that we are borderline insane, giving
away so much good information, they go,
"I must hire this person." So let's
look at another example.
Let's say you're a copywriter for a small
business,
and you work with brands.
You could create, I don't know,
an autoresponder
that divulges people into the biggest
mistakes, misconceptions, and errors that
people make when they try
and operate their sales
and marketing copy themselves.
That's the pain point.
They're trying to do it themselves.
So,
or even let's say you're a graphic
designer or better yet,
a thumbnail designer.
You could run a long educational series
that are going to help people with
improving their thumbnails,
and you're only going to bring people
closer to you
every time you do this.
So whatever industry you're in,
you're thinking, "Right,
how could I really revolutionize
and change someone's life through sending
them
emails?" Now,
the question probably burning within your
mind is
daily? Surely that's too much. Well,
people
empty their inbox daily,
so why not be in there every day?
And this is the power of turning up
and not breaking stride.
It's why I think it's so important,
and this is where me
and other mentors in the
industry are going to probably butt heads
on this,
but if I'm honest,
even when I was single,
I had a tactic similar to this.
If I liked a chick,
I'd want to go on several dates with her
within a
week because I'd rather get into it
and find out if they're right or not.
If I could only see her like once a week,
it could take me a month to realize if
she's flipping crazy, which
is looking back now kind of mad because
every single girl,
except my lovely partner, Taylor,
were mental,
and every time anything went wrong in the
relationship, it was
100% always their fault.
Statistically speaking,
the chances of that
are
staggering when you think about it.
But anyway,
say you're going to do 30 tips, tricks,
hacks, or whatever.
Surely you would rather hammer them every
day for a month than wait
30 weeks. That's nearly seven months,
you mad bastard.
So surely we are better off
[clears throat] getting all
that information
into their life, turning up every day,
because spreading it out is like having
squash and putting too much water in it,
right? You're just diluting it.
You're just making it shitter,
and someone's going to come along
and grab them and
make them their client without you.
And if someone can't handle a great email
sent to them daily for free,
which they can opt out of at any time,
trust me, they are not slipping off the
edge of their seat to do fucking business
with you. You know what I mean?
"Oh, James, you know,
that email sequence you put together
that was four and a
half months long, all that free time
that you put
together and the three books
that you wrote over three years,
and you assimilated
all that information into the emails,
I felt that they were just coming a little
bit too frequently." Fuck off, Sharon,
you twat.
You know what I mean?
Whereas someone will go, even
if you don't read them all,
they go, "I appreciate it.
He's turning up every day." You almost
want them to miss
you when the sequence is finalized.
You want them to sign up
and go through the whole sequence again.
Let them know if they can miss you
that they can have you back.
Have you back for good
if they join your damn program.
So think about that value,
think about turning up daily,
think about the
implications that could have to someone.
Okay,
so we've covered off some forces of the
squeeze and the deliverables and
the autoresponders.
So get your questions in to be answered as
I quickly cover up
some important details on these parts of
your strategy.
I'll have a sip.
Thought I could get a tactical sip here.
Okay.
Since 2015,
I utilized a different strategy called
famous daily emails,
which I took from Paul Moore.
That's why I call them squeezes as well.
But the thing is, people say
that I've robbed Paul Moore. I didn't.
I studied under him.
If you take someone's idea
and never give them money, you're a
twat. But I paid Paul.
I paid Evil Bull Genius.
I bought his book. So
famous daily emails.
How can we distinguish the two?
If I pre-write emails to be sent in a
sequence,
send email one, wait 24 hours,
send email two, that is an autoresponder.
However,
if I sit down at my laptop because I just
got a parking
ticket and I want to make it a funny
email, that's a
broadcast.
So in email marketing platforms,
they'll call it a broadcast or a
campaign. Because that one email
is a campaign.
It is a marketing strategy employee,
where then you could look through
and you go,
"Oh, this campaign, this campaign,
this campaign, this worked,
this didn't." So
this leaves people thinking, "Okay,
so when do I send
broadcasts if I'm doing an autoresponder?"
Good question. Now,
you can just send them whenever you like.
If you are broadcasting as someone's
joined your autoresponder, they may
get two emails a day.
But the thing I'd like to make clear with
this is
fuck them. Because
if you have a great offering
and you're just trying to help
these people,
you might as well throw it on top.
Like I said,
better to have a list of people that
are like, "Jesus Christ, this
guy is trying to help me so much.
He's emailing me twice a
day." But that's only going to be for a
short period of time where your
autoresponder and the broadcast overlay.
You could segment them so it goes a little
bit differently.
But imagine this. Today,
the majority of you here have
got three emails from me.
So some of you might be like,
"James, that was just so many emails.
I get it that you're doing a free webinar,
but these three emails is a bit much."
Sorry that I'm here smashing Nu Tonic at
flipping 7:30 PM at
night on a Sunday so I can help you guys
out.
It's one of those things. Now,
when we get into email
marketing,
we need to look at actually something
that I've learned from sales.
So whenever someone buys something,
they often get something called buyer's
regret.
The person that signs up to your email
list is going to get email marketing
regret.
Everyone that buys a course straight away
thinks, "Have I just wasted my money?" So
in sales, you want to make sure
that person feels like they haven't made a
mistake.
So in email marketing,
we need to do the same thing.
So we need to make sure
that our first emails,
whether in a responder or whatever,
are super succinct.
Don't worry about call to action in the
first few emails, but get in the point
and get out.
Get in the point and get out.
Don't make the first email too long
because if you
spam someone with a really long email
after they've just signed up to the email
address, they're going to get that regret,
and they're just going to want to get
out of there. They're going to go, "Nah,
this is Didier dog shit.
I'm out."
But by day five,
we want them thinking how on earth did
they live
their life without these emails in their
inbox every day.
And then we can start whacking in a call
to action, an offer, a
dangle. As long as we make sure that the
emails are short,
and it'll take you a
while to build up to the point of getting
to
longer emails.
But don't shoot your load too soon.
In the onset,
we are so much better at having the emails
be
a little bit
too short than too long.
Okay. Please don't waffle in your emails.
There is nothing worse than seeing a
massive email from somebody
like, "Mate,
I've just given you my email address.
I'm interested in your business."
Don't waffle. And every few months,
go back to your sequence
and read it with fresh
eyes,
and you can make some amendments to it
because chances are there's
going to be some changes you want to do
with it.
Some golden rules surrounding this.
Don't make your emails longer than three
minutes for the first 10 emails.
After the first 10,
because they're going to kind of see the
value, you could maybe
say no longer than four minutes.
And for every email after that, I would
say probably no longer than five-minute
read time.
Because even if you're going to tell a
story, make a point,
do something, anything over five minutes,
I think is just a little bit of
overkill.
So one question before we get into the Q&A
you're
probably thinking is, okay,
who's writing these emails?
Do I need to get a copywriter?
Do I hire a member of staff?
Do I pass this on to the marketing team?
You.
And I know that some people, they're like,
"Oh, but I've got
a business. I'm the CEO. I'm the director,
James.
I actually, I've got seven
or eight staff myself." No.
I know you might not think you have what
it takes, but with writing or creativity
or anything like that, but this
is something that you learn
and you get better at.
It's something so integral to everything.
Like the first time you edit DaVinci
Resolve or Premiere, you're
shite. The first time you make content,
you're shite. But guess what?
If you keep turning up,
you get less shite,
and before you know it, you're a
flipping weapon. I have four GCSEs.
I've got no degree.
I've got really bad ADHD.
I got tested for dyslexia, dyspraxia,
and I spent years at school in the
cloakroom because they thought I had
really
bad learning difficulties, which
was undiagnosed ADHD.
I've now been writing creative emails
and thinking up content on the fly for
nearly
10 fucking years. And even now,
I think that I've made
more progress from year nine to 10 than I
made from year one to
nine.
So
like anything, the more that you do it,
the better.
And again, if you wanted to take up golf,
let me tell you this.
The more often you're down the range
whacking balls, the better
your golf gets.
It's one of those things
that so many people kind of
just... If you want to learn French,
trust me, the more time you spend
in France
The better your French gets. You see
what's happening there.
You want to learn the guitar,
the more times you get the
guitar out, the better.
[lip smack] You get my drift.
Okay. Write emails for a year,
you'll be a lot better.
And don't get too caught up about,
"Oh." Just start writing them. Okay?
Nothing is going to be a prerequisite to
action.
Now,
we are going to get into what to write the
emails about, but just before
that,
we're going to dive back in to the Q&A.
And again,
there'll be a link in the description,
but there is a
time-specific offer for this webinar
and people watching it. Okay,
so I'm going to read your questions.
Just going to quickly hydrate.
[ice clinking in glass] Hopefully,
you guys are
having fun.
Let's have a look at some of your
questions, shall we?
Okay, good.
Okay. Vicky Smith:
If you don't have a website to create a
landing page, what can
I use to get people's emails?
So you don't need a website for this.
You can use
lead pages,
but also email marketing platforms often
will create a integration page for you as
well.
So what I mean by this is,
let's say you go to AWeber, and on AWeber
they will host a page
that you can put a little picture
and a little bit of
branding on,
so then you can send people to that link.
So that's what I would use. And again,
you don't even have to host that.
If you wanted to do an exchange of like a
PDF,
they can host that on their websites,
or you might want to use something like
lead
pages. But yeah,
the email marketing platform will
happily host that for you.
Charlie Bullen: First thought for me
was to put a video in the emails, but
when people think you're talking to them
daily, would you say videos are not good
as you could see them when they
were created? No.
If I want videos,
I'm going to social media.
Emails is not a place I go to to watch
videos.
Also, emails,
let's think about reading on the train.
Let's think about the commute into work.
Let's think about having a shit.
Let's think about being at your desk.
There's something I call the right time
effect, where
the majority of purchases
that you make are going to be you sat at
your desk with
your wallet next to you
or your purse next to you.
So have you ever noticed
that you've got to pay your utilities,
you've got to pay
your bills, you've got to do all of this.
So you kind of sit at your desk
and you pay everything off in one go.
We want to
catch people at a time where they're
looking to read, not to watch.
It seems wild that you would put videos in
an email.
If you're wanting to get people to watch
your videos, you'd probably
put it on social media
or put it behind a paywall.
Gerald Lee, good to see you:
How often would you recommend sending
separate
campaigns outside of the during a period
of an email sequence?
We'll get into this in a bit. It depends.
If you've got something really compelling
that you could talk about that you think
could make you sales, get it out.
Dan:
Should we include a call to action with
every email to potential clients, or
can this look too desperate? This
is where a lot of the time we put it in
the PS.
So you can just write a really good email
and then
kind of just at the end, "PS,
if you want to work with me, click here.
PS, if you want to explore coaching,
click here.
PS..." So it can almost become part of the
email, but it's
also just a little bit chill. Like today,
I'm selling
my course with the link in the
description,
but the video's not about the link in
the description.
The same way the emails don't have to be
about the call to
action.
It can just be something that's there.
Jason:
The goal is to continue to get new people
to sign up to your sequence of
emails to sell to them.
What do you do once the sequence
is finished?
Well, make the sequence good
and long enough that they fucking
bought before the end.
Now what you can also do, if you have a
product, you could discount it.
So let's say they go through the full
sequence and
don't buy, you could re-engage them.
So imagine this.
So we use paid ads
and organic ads to get people into the
30-day email list for the
business mentorship.
If they get to the end of 30 days
and they don't
buy, we then sell them a cheaper course.
So that's why I made the short form
content creation course.
We've kind of said, "Hey,
you're not spending $1,000.
Are you going to spend 100?"
And even though the profitability
is a lot less on
that, we can recoup our marketing costs.
So you might, again, an example,
let's say you're a professional services
or a
PT and you're selling
your services.
You could then get to the end of the
sequence.
If they don't buy from you
or the autoresponder,
they don't buy from you, you could
then say, "Hey, here is a cheaper plan.
It's program only.
It's blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah." Same way that even in Jameswith
Academy, if
people through our initial sequence don't
buy a membership, but they trial,
once the trial runs out,
we then offer them different things.
We're just trying to recoup marketing
costs at that point.
But yeah, so
once the sequence is finished,
they would then get your broadcasts until
they
unsubscribe.
But ultimately you would want to make
that sequence so
good that they buy. But again,
some people take months to come through.
It's just the nature of the beast.
But yeah,
you can always broadcast to them on
top, but the idea is
that you'd want to convert those people
before that.
Okay. So what do we write emails about?
Well, for the responders,
they need to be strategically laid out
and I'm advising
the people, you get
your avatars problems laid out.
So a quick thing about avatars.
We all should know our client.
So most of the time when I'm talking
to people in fitness,
one of my favorite clients, her name
is Susan
Green. I know Susan's problems.
I know her financial situation.
I know what car she drives. I know
that she went to Slimming World, Weight
Watchers. I know so much about Susan.
And we need to understand our demographic
and their pain points.
If you don't know their pain points,
you can't talk to them.
Even in social media and marketing
and advertising, if you see an advert
online for a Ford pickup truck, it's like,
"Hello, mate.
Get down to your local dealer
and see..." And then if it's a Jaguar,
it's like,
"Head to your local Jaguar." They even
talk like the demographic
that they're trying to sell to.
So it's very important that you kind of
understand if you're talking to women,
you're talking about dropping a dress
size.
So
understand your avatar.
If you haven't done the work necessary,
you should probably
do a deep dive on it.
Because once you know your avatar,
you could then maybe write
out 50 problems that they have.
And that's why face-to-face coaching is so
good for a lot of PTs because you're
learning so much about people's problems.
So then you could probably cut off 10 of
those shitty ones out of the list of 50,
and you're still left with 40. Now,
as you populate the emails
You could end it with an obscure amount,
a bit like trimming the fat.
So then you have the 50 problems,
but before you know it,
you've got 38 ways to do
whatever it is. So,
broadcasts are the fun ones.
The autoresponders are the
ones that are very strategic with people's
problems.
And again,
this is why I think it's important.
The broadcasts,
the emails you send just on a whim.
For instance,
you could go to the cinema
and see a film you saw.
And if it's bad,
you could send an email going,
"If you thought that film was bad,
the only day you could have had a worse
day is to not join my program."
So, for instance,
there would be things
that happen in my life
that would make a good broadcast.
I did an email once where
I tell a story, and again, stories
are very powerful.
It doesn't have to be a massive story,
but my email said, "Today, I went to the
park in Coogee.
I've never done... Well,
I haven't really done this before.
I went onto the grass kind of far enough
away that people couldn't see, and I just
thought, I'm going to do it.
I know I shouldn't do it.
I know that if someone sees me doing this,
this is going to be very embarrassing."
I said,
"This is probably going to be better
if I close my eyes.
It's probably going to take about five
minutes,
and I'm probably going to be quite
embarrassed when I finish doing it.
But I know that if I just do this thing in
a park and hope no one sees me, that
in five minutes I could feel so much
better.
I could feel so much more de-stressed.
I could feel so much better about my day,
and then I can relax and..." And then I
made it seem like I was wanking in a park.
But then at the end, I was like, "Yeah,
I meditated." And then I was like, "What
were you thinking?"
And so they've kind of had a little bit of
a laugh, and I was
like, "Look, I'm trying meditation.
It's not my thing. Whatever.
You might not do online coaching,
but maybe you should try it out." There's
another
email that I wrote about a massive laundry
bill.
When I was with Darren in LA,
I just shoved loads of stuff in a
laundry bag in an expensive hotel,
and the laundry bill was
£550 for one night of laundry. But then I
made it a funny email, so people
were giggling at home being like, "Oh."
They thought they were having a bad day,
right?
They've stepped in a puddle.
They didn't wake up with a £550
laundry bill. Another email.
I still remember my emails because they're
little
stories that I've told.
I used to live with a guy called Iman in
Maidenhead, and
one night he couldn't sleep. So,
I wrote this email so pissed off.
He had sleeping issues, whatever.
And I put my PT kit in the wash.
I went to bed after rugby training,
and the machine was keeping him awake,
so at midnight, he gets out, and he turns
the machine off.
I get up at 4:45 to go PT people,
and all my
PT uniform is wet.
So I had to put on wet PT
uniform in freezing cold British
winter, and it was horrible,
and it made a good email.
So I said,
"You might have thought you had a bad
start to the day, but you didn't
go to work with wet kit on.
The only day you can have a worse morning
than going
to work with wet kit
is not to join my program."
So another reason
that I really like sending broadcasts,
which is one-off
emails, is if you think back in 2017,
everything in my life kind of blew up.
I came to Australia in 2017 with £3,000 to
my name.
I had to borrow money off my dad to buy a
sofa when we moved into our first flat
here in Bondi. By July of that year, I
was flying first class for the
first time in my life,
and I spent $6,000 on a flight.
On a flight.
I got home and realized my bed only cost
me $100 off Facebook Marketplace.
But I was traveling alone,
and a lot of you guys, even
when you can afford business class,
you're probably
doing it on your own, because
when you start flying with your partner,
you really
have to be earning good money.
So I sat in the lounge, and it
was weird because
everyone else in the lounge kind of knew
their way around.
I wasn't sure where I could sit
or where I could eat,
and can I take food from that
area to here? So I sat at the bar,
and I had about five glasses of champagne,
and I
kept shitting myself that I
was going to miss my flight.
And the stewardess was like, "Don't worry,
sir.
We're going to come
and get you before your flight.
You're flying first class.
We're going to..." All of this.
So I sat there, and I was hammered,
and I was feeling kind of emotional
about the ordeal.
So I opened my laptop
and wrote a heartfelt email to all my
email
subscribers, and there
was something quite remedial
and therapeutic about it.
Being a man,
you don't really express your emotions
that much, and I actually think
that I can express how I'm feeling better
in an email than I can do face-to-face.
And it was really a monumental part of my
life that I wanted to share with people,
and everyone that had contributed to my
life was on my email list.
And I think my email airports
or my airport emails are my favorite
ones to write. I'll get a pint of beer.
I'll open my laptop.
I don't know what I'm writing about,
and I will just talk about whatever
emotion
that I'm feeling.
And this moment will come for you soon,
right?
I had a son. I wrote an email.
[dog running] Sorry, my
dog's being annoying. I tore my MCL,
wrote an email.
I won a BJJ comp, wrote an email.
I lost all my matches at another comp,
I wrote an
email.
The hard part isn't writing the email.
It's relating it to a sales direction.
And even if you don't have a smart way of
connecting what your email's about
to whatever you're selling,
you can just write, "Well,
that has nothing to do with
my program,
but you should join it anyway." And
if you can only imagine a
world where someone fist bumps you in the
street and says they enjoy your emails
and that they read them
when they take a poo,
that's kind of the place you want to get
into.
You want someone to come past and go,
"Hey, mate, really like your emails.
They really help me with this."
Yeah. If you have any questions,
we're about to do another Q&A,
so get them in now.
But
the important thing is here,
if you do this and you become a mad
bastard and write these emails,
you can make tens of thousands of dollars
from a
single email. And my favorite thing now
is when I fly long haul, I get to the back
of the Emirates A380, get a coffee
or a cocktail, I sit down, and I sell
people into my program,
and it's enjoyable.
But yeah,
even if I'm on a flight where you can't
really
watch Netflix on a plane,
I'll even just say, "Hey,
here's my personal email.
Drop me an email if you want." The Wi-Fi
on a plane costs a fraction of what it
costs flipping,
what your marketing costs or
whatever would be.
But you jump onto the Wi-Fi,
do some emails, chat to people,
close some people for it.
And even on email, I just say to people,
"Hey, if you're
not sure if you'd like the program,
here's a month money-back guarantee."
The people you close,
they're not in your DMs.
They're better off in the inbox.
And the last thing we're going to say on
the broadcast is
I used to think you could broadcast daily,
but I'd say it's probably now better
when the time is right. And this
is what's good about having an
autoresponder is
you can pepper people really hard for 14,
30, 90 days.
And should they buy
That's great.
Then they get the less frequent broadcasts
on top.
So yeah, the email
is so important because you never know
what's around the corner.
An event, a book deal,
something out of the blue.
It's good to keep people peppered via
email.
And if they don't fancy you having them,
they can unsubscribe at any point, and you
can't forget that. Also,
if you have a video
that goes viral tomorrow, you want to
make sure you are collecting emails from
that.
And if you're not,
what's the point of going viral?
Okay,
so we're going to jump in some of the
questions now.
Charlie:
"I'm a dog treats/food/toy retailer.
I get the goal to sign up to a service,
but what if it's about getting people to
switch and spend their doggo budget with
you and not Amazon or Pets at Home?" So
straight away, right,
what can we debunk within the
industry? What toys are good for dogs?
Which toys are bad?
What kind of assets could you give to
people?
So you could say to someone, "Right,
I'm not just going to sell you dog food,
I'm
going to sell you the education about it."
So let's take this dog treats and food.
Boom. Raw diet.
Do you advocate for a raw diet?
Do you know what your dog should be
eating? I'm already thinking paid ads.
"Hey, my name's Charlie,
and I help dog owners feed their dogs
right.
You might think that kibble
is good for your dog.
I've actually created a series of emails
going to teach you how to give your dog a
raw diet." Cool. Over the next 20 days,
you're going to get an email a day that's
going to break down exactly why this
is important.
At the bottom of each of those,
try our food, buy our food.
Here's a guarantee for our food.
With the toys,
there's a series here on dog stimulation.
Is your dog poorly behaved?
Is your dog stimulated enough?
How much time should you be playing with
your dog?
How is the proper way to play tug of war
with a dog? All of these things.
So again,
every other dog treat/food/toy retailer
is kind of just selling
a product.
They're probably running paid ads
and putting it through Amazon.
You can differentiate yourself by making
this a little bit different.
When I got Alfie, I didn't realize I
was feeding him wrong until someone DM'd
me. Even when I got my dog trainer,
I didn't realize how much I was doing
wrong. And my dog trainer
was $1,000 for three
sessions. So if there were free resources
online
that helped me via email to be a better
parent to my dog,
I would feel so much more compelled to buy
their food or their treats or whatever
it is. So I think this
is a very exciting industry to be in,
Charlie.
If you can, [chuckles] "Hey,
my name's Charlie, and I help dog owners
look after their dogs better.
Over the next 92 days,
I'm going to be sending you an
email every day, which
is going to have advice with how to feed
your dog, how to
train your dog,
and what toys to use with your dog to get
the best satisfaction for
them." Here's a longevity dog series.
You know what I mean?
Would you like your dog to live longer?
What a hook.
Would you like your dog to be healthier?
Would you like to save money by not having
to take your dog to the vet?
What a hook. Sylvester Sweeney, how
are you?
"Is it worth advertising mini email
courses in sequence through email list and
opt-in specifics so you can separate them
via tags, or just give the full list your
emails on different topics?" I do think
that the
segmentation of lists is very good.
But when you're running it yourself,
it can just be a lot more complex.
I do like just running a main list.
Because you've got your fitness app,
right?
I just don't think
that you're going to have to segment
people too much
because
they're all kind of going the same place.
I'm not sure
really.
But I wouldn't give yourself too much more
work for the case of doing it.
When it gets into tags
and all of these segments,
sometimes I feel like
we can overcook it a little bit. Hayden:
"When you were a personal trainer, did you
have a specific demographic
or did you target both men and women
and age ranges?"
I targeted women between probably 30 and
45,
but that didn't mean I didn't train men.
It's just that my marketing,
when I would talk about fat loss,
I talk about
dropping dress sizes. But
that didn't stop dudes from coming to me
to get in shape
because even though I would say,
"If you want to drop a dress size, do this
challenge." Dudes are like, "Oh,
I relate with this guy.
I'm going to join him anyway." So I had a
demographic, I had an avatar, but I
didn't go,
"I'm only training women." Someone goes,
"Here you are, James.
Here's some money.
I want to join your program." You're not a
woman. So yeah.
Hux:
"Will be this recorded to play back later?
I have a four-year-old running around
doing my night." Yeah, this is going to be
online. "Joined the course a
while ago." Fantastic. It really is.
"Do I still get the updates on this?" Yes.
So you're going to get the email marketing
courses in there.
The silver play button course I'm just
finalizing now,
and once you're a member in
the mentorship, you're in. You're in,
and I'll keep adding
courses to it.
I'm actually going to revamp the whole
mentorship in the next few
months, and once you're in,
you get access to all of that
and the Discord.
"I've got a personal email
and a business email address.
Which one would you recommend I use for
this?" I use my business one. Yeah.
Imagine this, right?
I get people emailing me.
They want to do my thumbnails or whatever.
So one guy the other day,
he tried pitching for something,
and I said, "Bro, you've
emailed me from a fucking Gmail account."
You know that phone shop.
Not phone shop. Phone jacker. "Hello.
I'd like your bank account
and sort code details."
When someone emails me from a
Gmail, that's all I think about.
Imagine I said this a million times
before.
You wanted to book a wedding photographer
for your big day, and you go, "Oh, if
you're a wedding photographer,
email me." And someone's like,
"Goodweddingpics@gmail.com." Get the fuck
out. Yeah, never.
Your personal email address should go
nowhere near your business.
Elena: "Silly question.
How do you actually get paid from emails?"
Okay.
It's not a terrible question. All right.
So, the same way
that you don't get paid from social media.
Well,
you do get paid from social media a bit
with ads, but if I post a reel on
Instagram, I don't get paid. But if
that reel on Instagram grows
me 10,000 followers, and out of that,
2,000 watching my stories and they end
up clicking to sign up to a webinar.
And then from that webinar, they sit
and they watch, and because of that, they
click on the link, and then the link,
they buy the program, then I get paid.
So it's through the funnel. So
when I launched my
mentorship,
I had previous data from other things
I've done.
So I've done business-to-business events
in person, online,
for years, since 2018. So
when I launched the course,
I had 20,000 personal trainers.
I already had their contact information.
So before we even started running paid
ads, I think-
On the day that we launched,
I sent out two emails, and we did about
£175,000 from two emails in a day.
£175,000. Now, that is 10 years of work,
right? And accumulation and social proof,
and it's not
like a day's rate or whatever, but
that's how you get paid.
You send people to it.
Again, when I wrote my first book,
I hit the email list of 100,000 people,
ask them to pre-order my book.
You get paid.
Then
New Tonic,
we've sold well over a million cans.
I think we've done nearly two million
cans.
So how do we sell New Tonic? Do an email.
We just restocked. And again,
I think we sold out
again, probably do six figures
when we restock the cans.
So emails are just such a great way.
So imagine this, right?
If I say to you, "Hey,
buy my drink." You're not like, "Mm,
cool." But if you
read an email from me where I tell you
that I've
sunk my heart and soul into this,
it's a project that's really important to
me.
Like this project potentially could mean
that I get to pay off my parents'
mortgage before they downsize, which
is actually a legitimate goal of mine.
My mom and dad can't afford their mortgage
when it comes off a fixed rate.
I will obviously take
that over for them if that
was the case because I don't want
to watch my parents have to downsize.
But for me,
if in two to three years' time,
a big drinks brand came
and wanted to acquire a percentage of New
Tonic, that's
my nest egg to potentially mean
that my parents can live in their house
forever.
But I can't tell you
that story on social media because you'll
just be like, "Oh,
boring."
And again, if I say that on social media,
the majority of people that follow me
online don't care that much.
But do you know who does care?
People on email.
And the people that read my emails
are the type of people
that would read through
the full story, and they'd go,
"Fucking hell.
So if I buy this drink, not only
is it this pretty good product,
I'm actually
contributing to James
having a power play where he gets to
prevent his parents from having to move
out of
the home that they lived in for 30 years."
That could be the emotional connection
that you needed with someone to then
eventually go, "Do you know what? Fuck it.
I'm going to buy it." So that's how you
get paid via emails.
Okay,
we're going to move into the next segment
of it.
As far as another golden rule,
I think you should aim for 10% to 20% of
all your
followers to be on your email list.
If you do not have that many,
you need to rookie numbers.
You should run campaigns to grow your
following,
like planting seeds as a farmer.
And when the time comes to harvest,
you should reap their emails.
And remember,
a farmer waits a year to get the crops,
so don't think you can do
this overnight. So yeah, whatever amount
of followers you have,
you want 10% to 20% to be on your email
list.
If you do not have that amount,
your priorities as far as strategy are
probably a little bit off,
because you've been prioritizing maybe
growing your following much,
and your funnel
will be maybe quite wide at the top,
and then it becomes super narrow, and it's
making it difficult for clients to come
through.
So when we think about how to get started,
let's reverse engineer the process.
Writing the email,
we want to break up the text into nicely
digestible sentences
where we can give people's eyes nice
breaks from the line.
You know when you had that psycho ex
and you broke up and they sent that really
long message to you without any line
breaks, and you think, "Oh my God,
this person
is mental.
How did I ever sleep in the same bed with
someone who was capable of
writing a 600-word message without line
breaks?"
I actually do this when I'm on WhatsApp,
too.
I send and hit send after every sentence.
So if their phone isn't on silent,
it just goes bing, bing, bing, bing, bing,
bing.
Because I hate it
when it says the person's typing,
and you're like, "Mate, just
send the message to break it up."
Okay.
And covering in who do we send the emails
to?
You can set up segments. So for instance,
you may send marketing emails to someone,
and if they buy,
they could be moved to another list of
prospects where you can now
engage them as a client. However,
in the real world you want to live in,
you just
want to write emails so they're so good
that even when people buy your product,
they're like, "Oh,
I don't want to stop getting the emails."
So I had this, that
when people bought my product,
if they stopped getting the emails,
they would
complain. So I just keep them in there.
And it's worth noting
that as your brand
and business becomes more complex, it may
need separate lists. For instance,
I have this business,
the business to business business.
I have 400,000 on my James Smith Academy
list.
I have 20,000 on the IFS list.
I use MailChimp for IFS,
which I loathe.
I use Klaviyo for this business
mentorship.
I use SendGrid for JSA,
and I use AWeber for my most recent four
and a half
month automation that I'm testing.
So yeah, like I said before, it
is a four and a half month autoresponder.
It is an email every day.
It did take me a while to write,
but this is where the beauty of it is,
right?
I'll show you behind under the hood.
So I run a chatbot on Facebook, where
if anyone comments on Facebook,
they get a DM, and the DM says, "Hey,
I've written these emails.
They're really helpful.
It's got my three books in it." So my
email list actually
trickles and grows as time goes on.
Then I've actually started using a company
that repurposes my content on
behalf and posts it on Facebook.
So there is a company that we
use.
They go through all of my archives of
content.
They repurpose my content so
that it's optimized for paid ads.
Now we do a rev share with that company.
So they get, I think,
a good percentage of it.
But my ads on Facebook have gone from
$1,000 a week for my audio
views to $5,000. So not only
are we getting more cash from the ads,
but the
company that we bought
or paid to incentivize to
put this content through means
that my engagement is shooting up.
And if my engagement is shooting up,
there are so many more people that
are getting
chatbot automation sent to them.
So I'll look on my Facebook and I'll go,
"Oh shit,
that video that that company posted
is going viral.
There's 500, 600 comments on it,
and every single one of those is getting a
chatbot." And those people then join my
email list, and then
they get an email every day for four
and a half months.
So, even though I haven't emailed them,
they're getting emails every day.
I had someone fist bump me in the street
the other day, and he's like, "I really
liked your email today." I was like,
"Mate, I haven't sent an email in weeks."
So having something
that could be there in an automation.
Imagine this, just as off the top.
You set up a ManyChat automation
that DMs people about your email list.
And remember, it's not like, "Hey, guys,
join my newsletter.
Join my newsletter, guys." It's like,
"Hey, here is 42 ways that I can
revolutionize your insert problem,"
whatever. They're getting a DM. They're,
"Oh, that social media influencer
just flipping sent me a DM after I
commented on his video, the bastard."
What did he want?
He wanted to change my life for free help.
So then you get a video
that gets 10,000 views,
it gets 200 comments.
Out of those,
45 people join your email list.
They then get nurtured through the
automation, and
then you're going to be closer to becoming
a new client. You know what I mean?
So now we're moving on to the most
important things you must
and mustn't do when it
comes to email marketing, and we
are closing in towards the
gargantuan interaction Q&A at the end.
So the must-dos for email marketing.
Better to send an email that's too short
than too long.
Better to send an email that
is too short than too long, and it
is better to send
an email that's too short than too long.
Make each email valuable in some form,
whether it's funny,
educative, thought-provoking, emotional,
whatever it is.
Try to make them conversational.
Talk to them.
Not too much branding,
not too much color schemes or whatever.
Just be like, "Hey, mate.
Had a really tough day today because of
this.
This is how I'm dealing with it." Whatever
it is.
You want it to be like a message from your
friend.
Don't swear too much
or embark in spammy behavior.
There are inboxes and gatekeepers
that try and stop emails
that look suspect.
You can use nostalgia from old Facebook
posts. You can go look at your memories.
You can use ChatGPT to give you ideas.
You can use the news. You can be creative.
One email, I was like, "ChatGPT,
give me 42 ways to kill a zombie in an
apocalypse."
Cool. Made a good email.
Must nots for email marketing.
Do not sign people up without consent.
You must get people's consent to send
emails.
So they must opt in for emails.
You do not just add random people's whose
email
addresses you might have.
You must get permission to email them,
and if not, they
will mark you as spam, and
that can tarnish your sender's reputation.
So there are a lot of spammy email
marketing gurus out there, [swallows]
so we want to make sure
that we get good quality people.
We want to have a good reputation.
As far as time of day,
don't worry too much
about when you're sending an email.
If it's during work hours,
it's probably got more chance of being
read and not
being marked as unread.
If you send it overnight,
they might get into the office
and be like, "Not today,
mate." Don't lose sleep over your open
rates and
click-through rates,
or you will just end up depressed.
Any of you that have tried to conquer
YouTube, you will know there is so much
depression from looking at click-through
rates and, "Oh, I've had a 10 out of 10.
Oh, what's going on?" Don't look.
Just keep sending out emails, and
don't worry about the amount of sign-ups
that you're getting.
I sent emails for 10 months.
There wasn't chat DM
automations in my day. When I started,
I was writing blogs on
WordPress. So I was writing blogs in 2014
about potato versus sweet potato,
and at the end of that,
I would put a little
hyperlink that said,
"If you want to hear more from me,
you can sign up to my
famous damn email." So in my day, it
was so much more difficult to get emails,
than
it is for you now. And back in the day,
with my little email list,
I sent emails for 10 months before I made
a sale.
I cannot explain this to you. There
are so many things I did
back in the day where people thought I
was crazy, but there
was no one on YouTube.
There was no people that I could talk to.
I was just sat in Waitrose, in Bracknell,
on my own, sending emails to
fucking no one on the internet.
Then one day someone bought.
And I can't even believe
that all these years later I'm
talking about making £10,000 from an
email.
It took me 10 months to make one sale.
And I'm kind of so proud of the
fucking nutter that sat through there for
10 months.
And then before I knew it,
when I moved to Australia,
I sent an email, I got 10
clients.
I literally just sent an email going,
"Hey, I'm 27.
I'm not sure what I'm doing with my life.
I'm thinking of going to backpack in
Australia.
If you want me to coach you online," boom,
10 clients, £550 a week.
Absolutely crazy.
Do not worry about your list size.
Worry about its performance.
You might have an email list of 1,000
people.
It might pay for you to fly first class.
My email list was 500K.
We just deleted 100,000 contacts because
we're cleaning it up.
If they're not opening the emails,
I'll get rid of you before
you unsubscribe. I want my list clean.
My good mate, Diran.
He's grown his lists hundreds of thousands
in Turkey.
But this is my problem with Diran.
I'm going to call it "Don't do the Diran."
Some
of you have email lists
that you don't use
and you're worried to engage with.
And I said this to Diran.
I said,
"Imagine sending so many emails
that your email list, the one you're
showing off about," because Diran's like,
"Yeah, bro, I've got 450,000 email
addresses." I'm like, "That's cool,
but do you know what would be cooler?
If you halved it." Because think about
this.
If you have 500 people on your email list
and you're not using it,
imagine sending so many emails
that you only have 100 people left and
400 people have unsubscribed.
And some of you are thinking,
"That's crazy.
Why would you want that?"
But wouldn't it be better to have 10 to 15
more clients
and have less people on your email
address?
That's why we do this,
because we want more clients.
If your email list keeps growing,
you're probably not hammering it hard
enough.
I said, "Diran,
would you not be cooler than you having
400,000 people on your
email list getting 300,000 of them to
unsubscribe than to get 100,000 of them to
become a paying client?" Because, again,
having a big email list isn't
going to pay for your wife to fly business
class to Dubai. All right.
So we've covered off some of the things
that are very important here.
Just before we get into the Q&A,
the reality is for a lot of you watching
this
webinar, if you do join my mentorship,
you'd only need to take one to two clients
to pay back on your initial investment.
That's the truth.
As a PT client or whatever, one client
is probably worth more than
$1,000 to you anyway.
And I don't mean to blow my own trumpet,
well, I'm going to anyway, but most of
these gurus that you follow online
are just good at ripping people off for
money.
I see so much of it. "Oh,
I've just paid £7,000 in paid ads." I'll
be honest with
you now, the offer is $1,000 US,
and that's not a lot.
I oversee every edit.
I script and write all my YouTube content.
I design all my own thumbnails.
The thumbnail for this video took me an
hour.
I had to get the font from Gmail to make
it look right.
I write all my marketing emails,
and I've tried hiring people before.
I've tried
hiring people and paying them £100,000 a
year.
You need to become the expert. And
if you think 1,000 US dollars
is a lot for my
course, try hiring someone that
is shit at their job
Because you've got to fucking do their
super, and you've got to do their pension,
and you've got to do all of this stuff.
If you really want to get to the next
level,
you need to become the black belt in
these areas.
You need to stop fucking thinking
that you can hire people to make
your problems go away. Yes,
you want to delegate.
Yes, you want to hire people eventually.
But you've got to stop avoiding the
things.
You think someone's just going to come
make good content for you.
No,
you need to know how to make good content.
Because even though I hire an incredibly
good videographer, I still need to
say to him, "Hey, Jacob,
I want Rembrandt lighting. I want this.
I want that." Because
if you can't direct and have
the vision for your business
and your brand, no one
is going to come along and care
as much as you care for your business.
And if you think
that you can give someone 100 grand a year
to care more than you
care about your business, I've tried it,
it doesn't work.
And I'm going to show you everything
that you need to know
that I've learned over
10 years,
for a fraction of what these other twats
charge.
And I know what you're thinking. Why
is my course so much
better value than everyone else's?
The people out there
that charge three grand a month
or whatever, or
10 grand for the year, or pay monthly.
Why is mine only a $1,000 one-off fee for
this offer today?
It's pretty much because I have a massive
following. That's pretty much it.
I don't need to charge so much because I
know how many people I can get on this
course. If I had a small following,
if I had only 10,000 followers,
I would have to charge you all 10 grand
each. Why?
Because I've not got any followers.
And
this course,
full transparency,
I'm in my Discord all day, every day,
and someone said to me the
other day, they go,
"James,
why are you helping us so much in the
Discord all the time?" I said to him,
"Mate,
to be honest,
I'm doing about 6,000 US dollars a day
with this
business." So trust me,
I'm happy being in the Discord.
I'm happy learning your businesses.
I'm happy doing this because I have so
many of you
that want to be in this mentorship
that I don't need to rip you off,
and it makes
me feel better. And the truth is, if you
really tried really hard with all the
stuff I teach you and it didn't work, just
send me an email. You know what I mean?
That's what I'm saying.
Just send me an email,
and let's have a chat.
I'll get you on a fucking call
if we have to.
And I've done it before with other people.
So the offer's in the description.
We're going to get into some of your
questions now.
Yeah, I appreciate you all for jumping in,
but that's it.
I don't rip you off because I'm living
good.
I'm living good.
And I'd rather help more of you for less
money.
Cool.
How do you develop the confidence to speak
on camera, especially on social
media, you sorry service? Ten years.
Ten years. Ten years.
Ten years.
Instagram alone. Let's have a look.
Let's do this.
Let's do this. 4,530 posts.
4,530 posts. So,
if we go
4,530 divided by
365,
that's a post a day for 12 years.
I've been busy.
It sounds crazy.
Imagine if you didn't get better
after doing something for 10 years.
My jiu-jitsu is so much better than it
used to be. Why?
Because I train loads of jiu-jitsu.
I obsess over it.
I study instructionals, whatever.
So if you want to get good at talking on
camera, you just need to talk on camera
more. It takes time. It's not easy, but
you're not going to meditate your way
through it.
Same as with anything.
It's so integral
that you become very competent in what you
do. Hayden, what would you say
is the most optimal method of getting
people
on the gym floor to sign up to your email
list?
You could put a fancy QR code or whatever,
but the gym floor is a
rubbish place to get people on your email
list.
Because all of these funnels
and automations, if you're in front of
someone on the gym floor,
just sell to them. "Hey, free session.
Hey,
consult." It's going to be so much easier
to do that.
To send them to an email list I don't
think is just good.
What I would do is maybe collaborate with
the gym to say, "Hey." If
people have signed up for email marketing.
So I did this.
When I started in a gym in Bracknell,
on my first day, I went in, I said to the
manager, "Hey,
can I introduce myself to the members?
I'm not going to sell to them.
I just want to introduce myself to them."
He goes,
"Cool." He goes,
"This many of the members have signed up
for marketing emails."
Cool. So I send an email. "Hey,
my name's James.
I'm not here to sell to you.
I'm on the gym floor.
If there's anything you need,
you want to ask me anything,
I've got five minutes for absolutely
everyone here.
And I'm a new trainer here,
so I've got more time than I know what to
do with."
I got 16, 17 clients from that one email.
If you're on the gym floor,
I wouldn't be getting people's emails.
This should be the stuff you do
when you finish work.
So Hayden,
you should be in the gym servicing your
clients.
Every time you leave the gym,
do a lap of the gym,
get a consult booked in,
whatever.
I'm not going home before I book a consult
call.
But then when you open your laptop at the
local coffee shop, that's where you're
creating social media posts with the end
game of eventually getting people's
emails. But again,
Gary Vee calls it the jab, jab, jab,
right hook.
You might want to do 10,
15 social media posts,
get the engagement really churning
in the back end, then boom, right hook,
video, call to action, chatbot,
DM automation, grow the email list.
So, yeah,
I think it's counterproductive to get
people on the gym
floor to join your email list.
This should be for
everyone else,
because it's just not going to be worth
it.
Jason, just moved to the Gold Coast,
started fresh at a new gym with 8,000
followers. How could I mine them
and try and collect as many emails as
possible?
If the gym's got 8,000 followers. No, bro,
you know what?
You don't want their followers.
Grow your own following.
Don't try and mine the gym's.
Make fucking good content.
You are one video away from having a very
different life. Imagine this.
You make one video
that goes flipping mental. Tom Bailey PT.
Yes, he's my mate. Yes,
he's in the mentorship.
Let me tell you about Tom Bailey PT.
English lad, lives in Bondi.
I gave him free access to the mentorship
because he's my mate.
We play Call of Duty together.
He did a video where he
did the Coke Zero,
and he did the can swap,
and he was like,
"You could save yourself some calories,"
or whatever.
I screenshot that. I don't message Tom,
and I gun him in the Discord.
I say, "You fucking bellend.
You're a good-looking lad with a British
accent.
You got into the kitchen to make content,
and that's what you made, a six-second
reel where you read the caption." I
was like, "This is a fucking cop-out,
mate.
This is lazy. This
is not good quality content,
and you're not building
relationships with people." So he goes to
the butcher, and he buys two cuts
of meat to represent the amount of muscle
that you can gain in a certain period of
time. That video went viral.
Greg Doucette shared it.
Ben Carpenter shared it.
He's gone up maybe 30,000, 40,000 or
50,000 Instagram followers because of it
From one video.
Now that is gonna impact his email list.
It's gonna impact his bottom line.
It's gonna impact the demand for his
coaching. It's gonna change everything.
Now,
Tom obviously had to create content for
months, be a trainer, all of that.
So for you guys out there,
rather than trying to mine a gym's data
collection,
get fucking good at making good
content. Because last week,
my manager said to me,
"You've not been on the New Tonic page
much." I've had a
baby, whatever. He goes,
"We need to see your face a bit more on
the brand page." I
go, "Yeah, fair." I meet my videographer,
I make a reel.
I say to my manager, "This
is going to get a million views.
Let's have a look." I was like. "Oh,
you want me to promote New Tonic?
Leave it with me, mate." And what we at?
One million views.
The fact that I now know if you say,
"James, I need you to get a
reel tomorrow with a million views in." I
can do it. I could do it quite easy.
I probably should've put a chatbot on
that, and I could've got loads
and loads of
emails from it.
But you need to become good enough to
create content so that at any
given point you can send traffic in
directions.
Catherine, good to see you here again.
"Your mentorship is unreal.
I made more than my investment back in the
first three weeks." And I've been
enjoying going through your content,
Catherine.
Been good to see your confidence.
You have a fantastic set of arms on you,
which I like seeing in the content, right?
You're a weapon.
Captions needed a bit of work.
You want to make content in your kitchen,
but I said to you it has to be
contextual.
I still even remember all the
conversations I have with people in here.
And Alfie: "Is there a timeframe for
when you have to complete the course?" No.
It's a one-off fee. Once you're in,
you're in.
Some people buy the course,
they don't look for a few weeks.
Some people lurk around for ages in the
Discord without doing anything.
It's fine. I'm not going to rush you.
The quicker you can do it, the better.
And imagine this as well, this
is something that I've told people
forever.
If you were to do the course and you
were to say, "Oh, James, I wish you'd done
this, this, this,
this." I add the modules.
Someone said to me, "James,
you told me to buy the DJI Pocket Osmo 3."
I suggest I
did. He goes,
"I don't know how to color grade it
if I film in log."
And log is when you film
and it looks really gray,
but pretty much it's
a way of filming so
that you do the colors yourself,
and it comes out a lot better.
So I hired someone to come teach me how to
do color
gradings in DaVinci Resolve,
and I just added the module.
Someone then said, "Oh,
I don't know how to use..." Well,
actually, Sylvester
Sweeney, who asked a question earlier on,
he jumps on a call with me to teach me
about ManyChat when we started it.
So I'm even learning from people inside
the mentorship.
And if there was anything that you said,
"I want to be covered off more," I would
add it to there.
And if you really went through the course
and you're like, "Oh, I didn't learn
anything," I'd say you're a fucking liar.
All right.
Really enjoyed doing that.
It's been a great chat. The link
is in the description.
Join. It's currently this offer,
1,000 US dollars. Jump in.
It'll be great for your business.
Again,
most of you take creatine because it gives
you a fucking
10% increase in gains. Right?
And 10% increase in gains, is that to you.
Honestly, learning content, social media,
email marketing strategy, all of these
things,
you're looking at a phenomenal amount of
return on investment, and you really,
really should
invest in yourself.
But yeah, as you can tell,
I enjoy doing this.
This is probably what I'm going to be
doing for the next five, 10 years.
Chapter one: personal trainer,
calorie deficit, books.
This is actually what I enjoy the most.
It's been a real revelation for me the
last year.
I actually
love helping brands
and businesses go well.
I love teaching people what I did because
doing this changed my life and made my
life so much better.
I have so much less stress.
I don't have to worry about money.
Everything's great,
and it wasn't like this.
When I was 27, my business
was very average.
I drove a cat C Volkswagen Polo,
which means it was written off before.
I moved back in with my parents at 26.
I never really had anything going for me,
and getting good at
content, social media,
and all this marketing meant within a few
years,
people spoke to me differently.
It's been absolutely wild,
and all of you can do
the exact same. You can. I'm not
that smart.
Like a space rocket taking off
into outer orbit,
you've got to use the majority of all you
have to do the first
10%. Once you get off the ground and just
start making it into outer orbit,
once you're up there, it's easy.
Once you learn how to make content, edit,
and all of this, it's easy.
The hard part is probably the next two,
three, four, six months in front of you.
If you can go balls to wall the next six
months, the rest is easy. You just coast.
Guys,
really much appreciate you being on here.
Click the link in the description, and
I'll see you guys soon.
If you have any questions,
probably drop me an email because I'm here
every day.
Thanks for being a part of it. Bye-bye.